Marvin Blake Rochelle

3700 W 16th St Panama City, FL 32401 (256) 404-1521 blakerochelle@gmail.com

I am front end web designer and user experience advocate in search of a company that values creativity and innovation as well as an environment that will provide a permanent home that I can continue to learn and grow with. I have more than 20 years of experience in the technological services industry, including 15 years in all facets of web development, from personally meeting with clients to discuss goals for their application, to research and analysis, design, development, testing, and implementation of code and applications, as well as a variety of graphic design and artwork when needed. I also regularly perform additional tasks including testing, technical support, project coordination and publishing. Over time, I have developed sustained relationships with internal management, employees and customers based on knowledge and trust.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Tools and Skills: Sketch, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD, Foundation, Bootstrap, PatternLab, Responsive design, User-centered design, Agile and Lean development

Languages: HTML5, Sass, JavaScript, PHP, jQuery with a working knowledge of AngularJS and Java.

EXPERIENCE

Kemper Company, formerly Infinity Insurance Company Birmingham, AL 2010 – Present

Auto insurance provider.

Systems Software Developer - UI/UX Specialist

- Utilize usability, user experience design, user interface design and interaction design along with front-end development to create consumer facing and internal web applications utilizing tools and skills, including HTML, SCSS, Responsive Design, JavaScript, PHP, jQuery, etc.
- Promote and ensure a consistent look, feel and experience across multiple Kemper domains and platforms.
- Define user experience concepts, provide design layouts, workflows, prototypes and high-fidelity graphics using a host of tools, which include Sketch, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator & XD, InVision and Balsamiq.
- Create and maintain libraries of reusable web components using Pattern-Lab, HTML, SCSS, JavaScript and jQuery; created content to be reviewed and approved by marketing + business stakeholders and utilized by product development.
- Develop and facilitate UX workshops to help identify and define interaction and usability requirements in order to help promote and provide optimum user experience across the organization.
- Currently fill the designer role on a balanced team, where I help lead ideation, technical design and the launch of innovative MVPs. Help establish a shared vision across the company by building a consensus on priorities leading to product execution. Work directly with business leaders, stakeholders and users to develop strategies which improve performance, usability and effectiveness of applications while ensuring that users are considered at every phase of the product development process. Communicate both independently and collaboratively with the business, users, relevant industry groups and project teams to bring a holistic, innovative and user-centric design discipline to the development of solutions. Analyze product needs at various stages and ensure relevant user research activities are performed (i.e. research/test protocols, questionnaires, user profiling, analytics, usability testing, etc.) in order to mitigate associated risks.

Red Mountain Technologies Birmingham, AL

Information bureau for the automotive and insurance industries. Lead Web Developer

- Utilize user-centric principals, design, develop, deploy, and document Web based applications that benefit both our customers and internal users. Applications are developed using HTML, CSS, JSP, JavaScript, STRUTS 2 and ASP.
- Maintain existing Web based applications to ensure their accuracy and currency as well as diagnose and troubleshoot any problems.
- Maintain proper documentation for many job functions, including preparatory information, detailed process instructions and day-to-day activity notes via company blog using Movable Type.
- Regularly perform technical support duties when needed. Support functions include customer interaction and training, troubleshooting and system monitoring with interaction via SSH and SQL Advantage.
- Served as project coordinator for the IT department which involved managing day-to-day project goals as well as long term goals for the technical staff.
- Plan and prepare the company newsletter for mail and online dissemination.

AutoCheck Auctions Birmingham, AL

2002 - 2003

2003 - 2010

Vehicle history data provider to over 95% of the auction industry. Customer Service Representative

- Interacted one-on-one with customers to help serve their individual needs.
- Coordinated with management to strengthen the relationships with our customers.
- Analyzed various databases to check the accuracy of historical vehicle information.

EDUCATION

UX Certification

October 2016

Nielsen Norman Group

Major: Management Information Systems

Bachelor of Science, Business Administration

December 2001

Auburn University, Auburn, AL

Major: Management Information Systems